Tommy Roberts

Game Designer

1821 W Callender Ave. #2 Peoria, IL, United States, 61606 tommyrobertsms@gmail.com (224) - 244 - 2609

As a passionate and dedicated game programmer, I am driven by the desire to bring immersive and engaging gaming experiences to life. With a solid foundation in programming languages such as C++, C#, and Python, I have honed my skills through coursework and personal projects, demonstrating my ability to design, implement, and optimize game mechanics and systems. I thrive in collaborative, creative environments and relish the opportunity to work alongside talented designers and artists to transform ideas into interactive realities.

Key Skills

- Game Design: Proficient in designing game mechanics, creating game prototypes, and developing engaging gameplay experiences.
- Game Engines: Familiar with Unity, including level design and scripting.
- Coding: Strong knowledge of programming languages (C#, C++, Java, Python) for game development and object oriented programming.
- User Experience (UX): Understanding of user-centered design principles to enhance player experience.
- Problem Solving: Strong analytical and critical thinking skills to address design challenges.
- Team Collaboration: Effective communication, collaboration, and leadership in multidisciplinary game development teams.
- 2D/3D Art: Basic proficiency in Adobe Creative Suite, Blender.

Professional Experience

Pool Manager

Park Ridge Park District | December 2017 - Present

- Trained and supervised a staff of over 150 lifequards during the summer season.
- Created and maintained an accurate pool schedule.
- Assisted in the development and implementation of pool programming and special events.
- Ensured the smooth and efficient operation of the pool, including maintenance of safety standards, facility cleanliness, and customer service.

Front of House Server

Dac's Smokehouse | October 2022 - February 2023

- Provided customers with menus and answered questions about menu items.
- Took orders for food and beverages and delivered orders to guests in a timely manner.
- Processed cash and credit card payments.

Package Handler

Fedex | December 2021 - January 2022

- Loaded and unloaded packages weighing up to 200lbs with speed and accuracy.
- Maintained an organized and clean work environment.

Education

Bachelor of Science in Game Design; Minor in Computer Science & Information Systems

Bradley University, Peoria, Il | August 2021 - Present

- Game Design Fundamentals
- Game Mechanics and Gameplay
- Object Oriented Programming & Data Structures
- User Experience (UX) Design
- Game Development Tools and Technologies (Mostly experience in Unity)

Objective

Enthusiastic and creative game designer, seeking an internship opportunity to gain handson experience in the game development industry. My fascination with emerging technologies and my commitment to staying up-to-date with industry trends make me eager to contribute to cutting-edge game development projects. Hopeful to contribute my passion for learning more better programming practices, and creating interesting game mechanics to a dynamic game design team.

Proficient Software Development Languages

C#, C++, Java, Python